Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
You okay?
Yeah. fine.
Is Valya home soon?
No. Remember I told you
he's in Moscow for the night.
To meet this woman?
The woman you saw him with?
No.
You were right. I was being foolish.
What did she look like?
She wasn't even that pretty. to be honest.
She was older than me too.
Did she seem Russian?
What do you mean?
Like. do you think
she could have been a foreigner?
No. I mean…
I don't know. I couldn't hear them.
Why are you asking
so many questions about her?
I'm just trying to help you.
I'd rather not think about it anymore.
Maybe…
Maybe it would be wise for you
to go away for a few days.
Just to clear your thoughts.
So now you think he is having an affair.
I just…
I thought about what you said. and…
It's the only thing that makes sense.
Does it?
Could you stay at your parents' dacha?
Tonight? Without even talking to him?
I'm sure he would just convince you
it was all in your head.
Yeah. maybe it is.
If I were you…
If I were you. I'd leave without a word.
That way the guilt will eat him alive.
I'm gonna need some time alone.
just to think.
You mustn't wait. Tanya.
It's too important to be complacent.
Complacent?
You… You know what I mean.
What? No. I don't.
I'm just trying to protect you.
I don't need your protection.
I need to think.
Perhaps… Perhaps you should leave.
- What are you doing?
- You must listen to me.
He is not who you think he is.
He's betrayed his country. Tanya.
Oh. my…
He's working for the Americans.
passing them information.
- H-Have you lost your mind?
- It's the truth.
I wish it weren't.
but he will soon be arrested.
And I know you. I know you had nothing
to do with his crimes.
But if you are still here…
- Valya's a hero of the Soviet Union.
- …they'll arrest you too.
- He's an officer in the Air Force. No.
- Valya is a traitor. has been for years.
- Not possible.
- It's hard to get your head around.
- but we do not have much time.
- This is insane.
- I can help you.
- You?
Even if anything you said was true.
what are you gonna do? You're a secretary.
I'm not… Not exactly.
You work in administration.
I work in Building 12.
You're delusional.
I don't believe you.
I… I want you to leave.
What are you doing? Stop.
Stop doing that.
They have been listening to you.
To everything.
This is not happening.
Just get away from me.
Get out of my house.
You must leave Star City.
This doesn't make sense.
If they're listening. they'll hear.
They'll know you've warned me.
They won't.
because I'll get to the recording
before anyone else can listen to it.
Have you listened to us?
To me?
Oh. my…
Oh. my God.
I… I…
I need to talk to Valya.
No. you can't contact him.
You need to leave now.
or they'll arrest you too.
But how can I?
I will help you.
They don't let anyone past the front gate
without a pass…
I told you I'll help you.
I can get you a pass.
Meet me tomorrow at 11:00.
near Building 33.
You have to trust me.
Okay?
Hello.
Colonel Raskova is…
- What the hell do you think you're doing?
- What are you talking about?
You know what I'm talking about.
Arresting one of my essential people
and for what? For some… some pamphlet
he picked up somewhere years ago?
Well. the general secretary's banned
Fyodorov's work. and rightly so.
I don't have time for this. I need him.
You should be thanking me.
The ideas in that book are counter
to the spirit of the revolution.
Lyudmilla. please.
Must we play these games?
- We know each other too well for this.
- Do we?
You're punishing him
because you want something from me.
I'm providing you with
the security that this program requires.
That is the point of me. just as you said.
What do you want?
Chief Designer.
You all right?
I'm so sorry. Chief.
I was… I was reckless.
I put everything at risk.
keeping that book.
Yes. you were.
But it's been taken care of.
- How?
- I agreed to certain terms
with Colonel Raskova.
She needed cover with her superiors.
So now you've compromised
your integrity for my sake.
Life is compromise. Sergei.
Now come on.
We've got work to do.
Where are you going?
The Chief Designer has…
He's asked me to participate
in a training exercise.
You just got back.
Yeah.
It's nothing. just studying the effects
of long-term confinement.
Long-term.
Have you got another mission?
No.
It's training in Siberia.
Locked up with a few others.
You should be happy.
You're rid of me for nine months.
Nine months and you leave today?
- I meant to tell you. I just… I was…
- Wanted to sleep with me first.
No.
What happened last night was…
It was wonderful.
You can't say no to the Chief Designer.
You know this. Stasia.
It is just…
It's been some time
since I had the opportunity.
Well. you will get another mission.
I know you will.
Just be patient.
Don't worry.
When you come back from Siberia
or wherever you're really going.
you'll find another whore.
There will be plenty
throwing themselves at you.
Irina. please stay.
Let me make you some tea.
I couldn't. We've al…
They'll hear.
they'll know you've warned me.
They won't because I'll get to the
recording before anyone else can listen.
…this woman. The woman
you saw him with? Did she seem Rus--
Comrade. I need access
to check the day pass records
for a subject Krasilnikov
against my recordings.
Repeat the name.
Krasilnikov.
Very well.
Give this to the records officer.
MIRONOV APARTMENT
AUGUST 11. 1970
As you all know.
all manned missions are closely monitored
by the Security division.
and without approval
from the First Office.
we cannot even get you out of Star City.
let alone to Venus.
Which is why we've classified our launch
as the unmanned delivery of
a Zenit weather satellite
to Earth's orbit.
But you must still get
to Baikonur undetected.
How? They've got this place locked up
tighter than a frog's asshole.
You will be making the journey in this.
What is that thing?
It was designed
to protect scientific instruments
from high pressures on the ocean floor.
And it'll do the same for us
on the surface of Venus.
But before that.
it'll be your home for the next two days.
You'll be sealed in here in Star City
and then transported unseen to Baikonur.
You must be joking.
Comrade Chadha. it'll be
the first of many a long period for you
spent in confined spaces. I can tell you.
I guess we'd better get used
to each other's smell.
Once the bathysphere's been loaded
onto the utility module on the tower.
you'll then be able to move down
into the BIOS module.
then onto the orbital module.
and then. of course.
finally onto the descent module
for launch.
- Simple.
- After orbital insertion.
you will rendezvous with a refueling
module already placed in Earth's orbit.
Then you will conduct
the trans-Venus injection burn
and be on your way
before anyone is the wiser.
And then what? I mean. surely there'll be
no way to hide us at that point.
There will be no further need
for deception.
Especially when they realize
we've reached Venus
before the Americans even knew
such a thing was possible.
As a senior man.
naturally I should be the first
onto the surface to plant the Soviet flag.
It's 460 degrees on the surface.
You'd burst into flames.
Well. it wouldn't be the worst loss.
You'll only be doing a flyby of Venus
and using its gravity
to adjust your trajectory
back down to Earth.
While you're up there.
you'll collect as much data as possible.
and then. of course.
the bathysphere will be jettisoned
and sent down to the surface of Venus.
We can only hope that it will withstand
the atmospheric pressure long enough
to transmit its data back to Earth.
You must remain vigilant about exercise.
No human has ever spent this long
in zero gravity.
And we are very concerned
that bone loss and muscle atrophy
could become debilitating.
What's your excuse. Comrade Nikulov?
Yes?
I need access to the carbon copy
of the day pass issued
to Comrade Krasilnikov yesterday.
One moment.
You're mistaken.
There was no pass issued
to Krasilnikov that day.
Of course there was.
It's not in the file.
Do you think Colonel Raskova was mistaken
when she asked me to retrieve it?
- Well…
- Perhaps it would be worth
doing a more thorough search.
Yes. Yes.
I…
I'm sorry. but I-I cannot find it.
Very well.
What will you tell her?
Not to worry.
I'll keep your incompetence to myself.
- I'm gonna have to see your pass.
- No. You… You must be joking.
I-I need a pass
to go get my son some shoes in Moscow?
New regulations.
I'm tired of all these new regulations.
How are we supposed to live like this?
- I don't understand…
- Comrade. your pass was
only valid until 10:00.
- Step away or you'll be detained.
- No. no. Answer my question.
It's 20 to 11:00.
My apologies. the buses ran late…
- When did this happen?
- …leaving Moscow.
I'm sorry.
I will have to make a note of this.
Come on.
You do that and suddenly countless people…
- I need to see a pass.
- …are gonna spend countless hours
chasing down the fact
that a bus had a flat tire.
Do you think that's
the best use of the state's time.
of your time. of my time?
Do you know who I am?
I've been to space and back.
Yeah. you recognize me now?
Apologies. comrade.
Apology accepted.
- Wait.
- No. you didn't check
- you were in the correct altitude.
- I followed the procedure.
Mission failure. loss of crew.
About time. Valyush. Where have you been?
Not now.
- You were pointed…
- Excuse me.
…in the wrong direction during the burn
and missed the window
for the Venus transfer orbit.
You can't run it properly.
Time to insertion burn.
Engine ignition in 15 seconds.
Have you checked
the propellant valve configuration?
Have you armed
the automatic sequence for the burn?
The burn is armed.
Propellant valves are opening.
And engine start.
Mission failure again.
You are now heading into deep space.
- Again.
- Reset the program.
And we'll watch the turbopump run-up rate.
Now. the auto launch sequence
has to begin precisely…
- Chief?
- …at this spot.
- Chief Designer. may I have a word?
- Excuse me. one minute.
Yes?
I… I just…
It's a-- It's about Comrade Chadha.
Yes?
I just feel that she…
She is… She is not prepared
for the rigors of this mission.
It would be difficult enough
with a well-trained crew.
I'm just concerned that
she may put us all at risk.
And let me guess who you have in mind
for her replacement.
She is the most qualified.
You know she has the will.
the ability. the skills.
Comrade Polivanov…
And if she is stuck down here.
I'm afraid what might happen to her.
If you want air to breathe
for the next nine months.
Comrade Chadha is the one person
in the whole of Star City
who knows how to operate that system.
But why not in place of Pavel. then?
I mean. Anastasia is the best.
- It's not about bests. Are you blind?
- Then why--
There's eyes on her constantly.
Her minder spends more time with her
than he does his own family.
And if they were to discover
what we're doing here. now. in this room.
we would spend the rest of our lives
in the gulag!
- Forgive me. I just…
- I know. Now go. please.
I'm sorry about last night.
No. I… I'm the one who should be sorry.
It's like I'm in a dream.
But at the same time. things are finally
starting to make sense. like…
The last minute trips to Moscow.
his mind just being somewhere else.
You know?
I knew something had changed in him.
I just blamed myself.
No. you're…
You're more powerful than you realize.
Take this.
What?
- How did--
- When you get past the gate.
get the bus to Moscow.
There's an address in there and a key.
Take the back entrance.
I don't think I can do this by myself.
You won't have to.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
and we can discuss how to
get you out of the country.
The country?
There's no other choice.
The families of traitors
are guilty by association.
- Would I even make it out of the country?
- Well. just let me worry about that.
What will happen to Valya?
You should put him out your mind.
You should go.
Please.
Why are you doing this?
Why are you helping me?
You should go.
Working with kids.
teaching music. You must love it.
I do. I love it so much.
- Before I came here…
- Send her in.
I was a rehearsal pianist
for the Moscow City Ballet.
- That's incredible.
- Yeah. it was.
And you said you worked in administration.
What does that mean?
Irina. You work in administration?
Colonel Raskova?
I'm basically just a glorified secretary.
Oh. I doubt that.
You have to be someone important
to get your child into that school.
Or be important to someone important.
That sounds nice.
Being important to someone important.
Our glorified secretary.
please do have a seat.
Comrade Yegorova here informs me
that you've grown quite close
to one of your subjects.
No.
Am I to disregard my own ears?
Of course not.
I did diverge from protocol when I started
visiting the Mironov apartment. but I…
It is a sickening breach
of regulation. Colonel.
Her child is even a student there--
That's enough.
What is it about her
that you find so enticing?
Is it her eyes?
Is it the way she smells?
Is it her willingness
to do just as she pleases?
No. Colonel. I was just doing my job.
That's why I've come.
My report lays out why I've been
infiltrating the Mironov residence
for the past few weeks.
Valya Mironov?
Yes.
He's the mole.
I'm sure of it.
I apologize for not…
letting you know my suspicions sooner.
but I know how important this is.
and I wanted to make sure
it was absolutely correct
before I presented it to you.
But she broke protocol.
If we're to abide by the rules
of the security services then--
Stand.
You seem more concerned with
causing trouble for your fellow workers
- than for your own subjects.
- Colonel Raskova. I was only--
Apologize.
I'm sorry. Colonel Raskova.
Not to me.
To her.
Irina Vasilievna…
I sincerely apologize.
For being an infantile rat.
For being a…
Infantile rat.
For being an infantile rat.
Dismissed.
Well. Irina Vasilievna.
it seems I've underestimated you again.
Let's hope your delay
hasn't cost us valuable time.
Do we know
the whereabouts of Valya Mironov now?
Well. he returned from Moscow this morning
but hasn't been to his apartment since.
Maybe he suspects that we're onto him.
Well. he wouldn't have
returned to Star City if he did.
Chief Designer's office will know--
Chief Designer will only get in the way.
We need to handle this quietly
if we're to contain the damage.
That's all for now.
Get me the Operations Directorate.
Valya.
Just going over the plans one more time.
Don't you worry. my Eagle.
the craft is sound. They'll be safe.
I know how it can be
before every launch. Always…
can't sleep. can't eat.
All the way back to Yuri.
In some ways. it's easier
being up there. isn't it?
Yes. I suppose.
The universe brings its own luck.
Forgive me. Chief Designer.
Valya. your wife went to
the training center looking for you.
Excuse me. what?
Your wife.
She's here?
No. she's waiting outside.
Sorry. do you mind if I…
- Please.
- I'll be right back.
Sure.
Thank you. Vitas.
What's wrong?
They know.
What?
- They know.
- Who knows what?
They know about what you've done.
- What are you talking about?
- Don't lie to me.
- I'm not lying.
- They're gonna arrest you.
- Do you understand?
- Who… What?
Do you understand?
You need to leave Star City.
Just hol… Just…
Just wait. just wait. What?
Tanya. Sorry. I tried everything.
- I don't want to hear excuses.
- I tried everything to stop it.
- You need to leave.
- I'm not leaving anywhere without you.
- Okay?
- Yeah. well…
I can get us out of here.
I can get us both out now.
What. with the Americans?
There's a woman…
There's a woman in Moscow.
She said to me. if anything goes wrong.
if anything goes wrong…
If anything goes wrong. I go down to the…
I put two marks on the café.
on the wall of the café
- in Gorkogo Street…
- Two marks?
…and then I meet her at Krymsky Bridge.
Krymsky Bridge.
- Marks at a café?
- She can put us both in a car.
- Okay. she--
- Listen to you!
You sound insane. I don't even…
- Please. just… Just wait.
- I'm not fucking going anywhere with you.
- No.
- I can get us both out of here.
- No. no. That's enough. Valya!
- Please. I didn't…
- I don't fucking trust you anymore!
- Please don't shout.
- I don't even know who you are.
- Yes. you do.
- No.
- Tanya. I did this for you.
- You need to go.
For me? You fucking ruined my life. Valya.
You've destroyed our fucking life.
You need to go.
- I'm not leaving without you.
- You need to…
Tanya. please wait. Tanya--
Don't touch me.
If you touch me again. I'll scream.
No sign of Mironov here.
Mironov's locker?
Okay.
Valya!
You okay?
Yep. just getting some fresh air.
Last one for nine months.
Here. take the packs. I won't need them.
The hardest part about the whole thing
is gonna be the next few days.
Locked in that jar. tighter than a Vostok.
When are you heading to Venera?
I was supposed to be there
five minutes ago. Better be going.
- See you in nine months. Valyush.
- Okay. good luck.
Pavel.
Pavel! Hang on a sec. One sec.
Where the hell is he?
I… I…
I'm hearing that something is
happening all over Star City.
It's heightened security.
- Do you think he could've been detained?
- Damn!
- Can we do this with two cosmonauts?
- Not without two pilots!
- Since we only have--
- The next window isn't for years.
This is our only chance.
I'll go to his apartment.
I'll try to find--
There's no time for that.
Sergei. We're already behind as it is.
Valya. There you are.
We need to find Pavel immediately.
- Pavel's not coming.
- What?
- He's been arrested.
- But how?
They're rounding people up
all over the city.
Raskova. she's gone mad.
Then it's over. It's…
You don't know that
he's told her about Venera.
It doesn't matter. The mission requires
three cosmonauts. and Pavel--
I'll go in his place.
What… What do you mean?
I'll go.
Well. what choice have we got?
I'm the only one that can step in.
I designed the training program.
I know what needs to be done.
Probably better than us.
Definitely better than us.
Are you sure. my Eagle?
Yes.
Chief Designer.
I know how important this is.
Thank you.
All right.
All right. Go on.
Get yourself into a flight suit.
- Glad to have you with us. Valyush.
- Yeah. Let's go.
We're loading up.
Help!
Let me see your manifest.
Baikonur?
Why wasn't this precleared?
Well. it has been
on the transfer manifest for weeks.
Equipment for the new satellite launch.
Open the back!
What's in there?
The Chief Designer's
latest weather satellite.
If we don't deliver the payload by launch.
the Chief Designer will have our heads.
What is this?
Maybe instead of looking at the weather.
it should be looking for these.
Open the gate!
Stasia. in case
I don't ever see you again.
I wanted you to know
that giving up is easy.
Living is hard.
You helped me realize that.
Amongst many other things.
Never been one for letters.
When they first had me write one
before Luna 17. I had no one to write to.
But now it seems I do.
I'm sorry for leaving.
For lying to you.
For not giving us the chance
to see what this could have become.
But maybe it doesn't matter.
The truth is…
you deserve better than me.
Whatever else happens on this journey.
I hope you are able to breathe again.
With love. your husband. Sasha.
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-